To build out our UI, let's start with the wire
frame for the main activity. It displays a list of
forecasts, where each item contains an icon, a date, weather
description; as well as high and low temperatures for that
day. Since today's weather is probably most relevant to the
user, we give more prominence to it as a list
item compared to the other days. We'll start off by
building the list item layout for future days because it's simpler.
And then afterwards, we'll come back to do the today layout.
In the current implementation, the list item forecast layout XML is
a horizontal linear layout of four text views. We'll need to
modify the layout so that it looks like this wire frame.
We should divide and conquer until we can use the view
group layouts that we're familiar with. Can you imagine how you'd
break down this UI into components that you know how to
build? As a hint, what if I draw these separators here?
Within those elements, can you find a way to
break it down even further with view groups you're familiar
with? You'll need nested view groups, which means view groups
with children view groups. As a tip, this data will
be populated dynamically at run time. But you can
test it by hard coding some text values such as
Tomorrow for the date or Clear for the weather condition.
For images, we can specify a placeholder drawable called ic_launcher.
It's named this way, because it's the launcher icon, which is also
known as the app icon. And this is already included in our
app. We'll be getting the rest of our weather icons for our
app later in this lesson. If you want to see what this layout
looks like, you can click on the design pane to see a
preview of it. On the right, we see a component tree listing
out the different views. We can also see for a given view
what the properties are, and their values. We can change the orientation
of the device that your previewing, you can also
select different devices such as Nexus 7, or Nexus
10. You can also preview multiple devices at the
same time. As you build out your layout for
this task, don't worry about the font color, or
font size, or any other visual details until later.
After you compile and run, the app should look
something like this. Check this box when you're done.